

PROLOGUE

Sitting upon the bridge of the ISS Manticore, Captain Des Spike mindlessly scrolled past the lastest headlines.

Captain.

Thirty years ago, he would have given anything to be in this position - in command of a supercruiser, out in the middle of nowhere - but that was {startYear} years ago. Then, everyone assured him he had a bright future, that he would make admiral one day - and for a while he {soared?}. He made Lieutenant Commander {x} years ago, then commander, then captain. People still reassured him then; told him that - given the officer-shortage - he’d get a promotion to the admiralty in five or six years. 

That was {y} years ago. He had done nothing of value since; shuttling delegates here and there and cataloguing nebulae - and, sure, that was important, but it wasn’t what he joined the navy for. It wasn’t the constant thrill of discovering new life and new civilisations that those officers that stood on the right side of the admiralty enjoyed. But just because he made one mistake; one error in judgement {y-1} years ago, as a newly promoted captain, he was sidelined; cast aside. //possibly remove ‘cast aside’

In the Cotton massacres, he stood up to his commanding officer, one Admiral {insignificant c.o. Name here}, and refused to fire on walls of civilians who were doing nothing but protesting. And that - officially - was the right choice. Unofficially, howerver, that made him a traitor. That made him someone who could not be trusted; someone who betrayed the naval brotherhood. 

In the years since, he had stood idly by as he watched other officers - some four or five years junior to him - get promoted to flag-rank; get command of various fleets, and doing what he should have been doing - going out there and exploring. But time and again he was passed over. //remove this maybe?

No matter. He was doing his job (charting the {system-name} nebula), and doing it well - even if that did mean reading sensationallist articles about how antimatter usage kills people and how there were(for the second time this month) futile protests about military reform and how warp drive “destabilizes your neuronic energy”.

Leaning back, he sighed in boredom, and closed his eyes.


*

Just over three-hundred light-years away, Admiral {Astelan-char-name} of the Astelans was celebrating his promotion aboard the AS {Astelan-ship-name}.
{IMPORTANT: decribe celebration. He feels tired at the end.}

The comms beeped, jolting him from his half-sleep. He groaned, and with great effort peeled open an eyelid - which saw that his friend, {astelan-friend-char-name} was going to get it.

The eyelid fell shut.


CHAPTER ONE
Six hours later, {Astelan-char-lastname} stepped onto the bridge - dimming his visor as he did(he had a head-splitting migrane) - and was greeted by complete chaos.

Clearly, something had happened. He remembered - vaguely - that someone had tried to reach him last night. But - no, that simply couldn’t be related - they would have tried harder - wouldn’t they?

He took a deep breath, and strode calmly to the center of the bridge.

<Report.>

The bridge fell silent. In every person’s mind, he sensed fear, nervousness, and a sense of disbelief; a sense of hoping that someone else would speak up.
Of course, no-one did.

He turned to his science officer(she feared nothing, and was always commited to integrity and the scientific truth), but to his surprise he found that even she was uneasy.

<{Astelan-science-officer-name} - what the hell is going on?>

She snapped to attention - again, odd: [CHANGE WORDING: in an effort to reduce tension when he was a new captain, he had made it so that attention was not neccesary]
<Sir, there is an inbound vessel. Initial measurements put its speed relative to this system’s sun at an approximate [very high speed], and we’ve - well, we’ve just confirmed it is travelling at [more precise vh speed].>

<Impossible - even we do not have ships that fast - let alone the rest of the cluster. The sensors must be broken!>

<That’s what i thought too, sir; but we’ve already checked and recalibrated the sensors.>

[Very high speed] was impossible. He knew that - everyone knew that. No current technology, nor even any theoretical technologies, considered that speed to be remotely achievable, even for weapons. But a ship, of all things, achieving that speed? That was simply absurd.

Nonetheless, it seemed that the impossible - in this case - was possible.

He took a deep breath.
<Ensign {ensign-name}, bring me a - >What was the word? Ah, yes - <Coffee, please.>
Coffee, being the exotic Icaran drink that it was, was expensive. But if he ever deserved coffee, it was now.

He paced, trying to clear his head. {ensign-name} brought him the Coffee; he drank it.
<Contact the {Carrier-name}. Ask them to verify and deploy scouts, deploy a level-two screening field with a tempoary screen and blockade on our position; and then prepare to retreat to standard ready positions. Communications, attempt a hail.>

*

“Captain Spike, we’re recieving an urgent inbound message.”

“Put it on.”

“It’s text-only, sir. Its from one of our frigates, the {frigate-name}, which was escorting a cargo convoy. They’ve been attacked by a {pirate-faction}-ship, and while they have scared it off have taken considerable damage. Appearantly, it is headed in our direction at - and I quote: ‘Impossible speeds’, and {frigate-name} requests we intercept it.”

“Reply with acknowledgement. Conn, sound General Quarters and plot an intercept course. Tactical, work with [replace: Astrology] and prepare a brief of the area of intercept and the enemy ship.“


Chapter Two - two hours later - spike.

Captain Des Spike - now dressed in full armor - strode towards the automatic doors of the briefing room.

He still couldn’t believe what was happening. Yes - the frigate being attacked was regrettable, but for once he was where the action was; for once, he had something important to do - even if it was a simple anti-piracy one.

As he stepped towards the doors, he stretched out his hand - the microchipped gauntlet transmitted his access code - the doors opened.

“Report.”

His executive officer, commander {XO-name-here}, replied. “Captain, we have confirmed the vessel to be similar to a {pirate-ship-class}. Assuming we depart at maximum speed in one hour, we will be intercepting them in quardrant five of this system at four O' clock - three hours later - which is ideal: it is devoid of asteroids. We have also confirmed the {frigate-name}’s report of the vessel travelling at an ‘impossible speed’: It is - in-fact - travelling at appoximately {VH}.”

“But…who even has engines of this class?”

“No-one, sir. That’s why it’s impossible.”

The room fell silent, as the officers gathered waited for that information to sink into Spike’s mind, and for him to give instructions.

That took a while. But, eventually, he spoke.

“Commander, proceed with the departure in…” Spike checked his watch. “Twenty-four minutes. Engage cloak and sound yellow alert, and inform me when we arrive.
Turning on his heel, he left the room, grinning to himself - finally, something exiting was happening!
*One hour and twenty-four minutes later
Captain Spike - now fully awake and refreshed - sat on the bridge, staring(along with everyone else)at the red dot darting towards them, as {XO-last-name-here}gave updates on its ETA.

"ETA: ten minutes!"
"Commander, load torpedo tubes," said Spike.{XO-last-name-here} Did so.
"ETA:





oswald font